Darshan Bhanushali

Jersey City, NJ 07307, USA | +15513447214 | dwarsh.b@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/dwarshb | developerspace.medium.com

SUMMARY

Experienced Android Engineer with more than 5 years of experience developing mobile and web applications. Proficient in Kotlin and Android development principles, and have implemented features improving user engagement and application efficiency. Successfully led cross-disciplinary projects, integrating payment gateways and APIs that increased revenue.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Soopra Al | San Francisco, CA

Software Engineer Dec 2023 - Present

- Crafting multi-platform applications using Compose Multiplatform for seamless interaction with AI personas, facilitating user-creator dialogue.
- Conducted code reviews and contributed to debugging sessions.
- Utilized Android Jetpack's LiveData for efficient data updates, enhancing user experience and responsiveness.
- Employed MVVM architecture and Dagger for dependency injection to create scalable applications.
- Implemented and maintained CI/CD pipelines, ensuring smooth and efficient deployment processes.

Inscripts Pvt Ltd | Mumbai, India

Software Developer Aug 2019 - Jul 2022

- Engineered reusable UI kits and a chat-widget for CometChat that is being utilized by 10,000+ developers and clients.
- Led integration of new payment gateway, reduces transaction processing time by 20%, increases client satisfaction by 40%.
- Participated in investigations when hitting the limits of scale, contributing to the stability and scalability of applications.
- Collaborated with 25-member team to deliver end-to-end solutions for client projects, utilizing Agile methodologies.
- Drove a 30% revenue increase by integrating video calling features, utilizing Kotlin and Android SDKs.
- Integrated Firebase, APIs, Geo Location, and VoIP Services, resulting in a remarkable 50% boost in productivity.
- Implemented Android Automation using Expresso, Robotium and UI Automator and wrote integration test cases.

Heer Properties | Mumbai, India

Software Developer

Jun 2017 - Jul 2019

- Crafted dynamic web applications with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, meeting industry standards for speed and scalability.
- Slashed page loading time by 18% and amplified search engine indexing by 8.6x, leading to a 200% surge in website traffic.
- Leveraged Google Analytics to manage and optimize events, resulting in a 33% increase in leads for the customer support.

Programming Language: Java, Kotlin, C++, SQL, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP.

Development Skills: Android Development, Web Development, API Development, Software Development Fundamentals Data Analysis: Data Cleaning, Data Visualization, Statistical Analysis, Python Libraries (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn) Tools: Android Studio, Google Play Publication, Firebase, Git, JIRA, Adobe Photoshop, Figma, Docker, Jupyter Notebook

EDUCATION

Stevens Institute of Technology Master of Science in Software Engineering	Sep 2022 – Dec 2023
 University of Mumbai Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering. 	Aug 2016 – Jun 2019
 Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education Diploma in Computer Engineering. 	Aug 2013 – May 2016

PROJECTS

• University Of Mumbai | Heart Disease Prediction System

Jun 2018 - Feb 2019

Created a sophisticated Heart Disease Prediction System, leveraging Machine Learning techniques and Flask in Python

• Stevens Institute Of Technology | ShiftDay

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

An Android Application that allows manager and employee to schedule the work shifts.

Stevens Institute Of Technology | <u>Fitness Connect</u>

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

A Dot Net-based web application, offering a comprehensive fitness tracking and social platform.

CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate for Completion of Java Training (1885589Q0R) | STP, IIT Bombay

Feb 2017

Certificate for Completion of Python Training (1202095A5C) | STP, IIT Bombay

Aug 2017

Aug 2018

Certificate for Completion of Java Business Application Training (1202095X2G) | STP, IIT Bombay